A Guide to the Papers of Joseph Carrington Cabell Relating to the Founding of the University of Virginia,
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1826 February 10, ALS. 4 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 370-372. (Box-folder 2:40)
  Action in the Assembly with regard to T. J.'s lottery. Bill to establish colleges throughout the state. References to James Madison, Chapman Johnson, and Hampden-Sydney College.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson. 1826 February 15, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 374-375. (Box-folder 2:41)
  T. J.'s lottery bill. Bill to establish colleges throughout the state.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1826 February 20, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 375-376. (Box-folder 2:42)
  Passage of T. J.'s lottery bill, with list of the votes of the senators. Bill for establishment of colleges throughout the state. Reference to Samuel Taylor.
- Proceedings of the Visitors of the University of Virginia, at their meeting in October 1826. 1826 October 2-7, AD. 16 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:43)
- Proceedings of the Visitors of the University of Virginia at their meeting in December 1826. 1826 December 4-16, AD. 21 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:44)
- Proceedings of the Rector and Visitors. 1827 July 10-19, AD. 14 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:45)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1828 July 10- July 24, AD. 12 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:46)
- Proceedings of the Board of Visitors. 1828 October 1- October 4, AD. 9 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:47)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1829 July 14- July 21, AD. 12 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:48)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1830 July 14- July 21, AD. 14pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:49)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1831 July 12- July 20, AD. 21 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:50)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1832 July 11-July 18, AD. 16 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:51)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1833 July 12- July 20, AD. 20 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:52)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1833 September 3- September 4, AD. 9 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:53)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1834 July 15- July 19, AD. 19 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:54)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1835 July 2- July 5, AD. 21 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:55)
- Proceeding of the Visitors. 1836 August 11- August 13, AD. 12 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:56)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1837 July 3- July 4 and 1837 August 17- August 18, AD. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:57)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1838 July 3- July 5, AD. 12pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:58)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1839 October 2, 1839 November 16, 1839 April 30, AD. 6pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:59)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1840 July 4- July 7, AD. 16pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:60)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1840 November 23, AD. 14 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:61)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1842 March 22, July 1- July 5, AD. 8pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:62)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1843 July 4- July 5, AD. 7 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:63)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1844 July 4- July 5, AD. 8 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:64)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1845 April 23- April 24, 1845 July 2- July 5, AD. 12 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:65)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1846 January 20- January 24, AD. 9 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:66)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1846 June 25- June 29, AD. 10 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:67)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1847 June 27-June 30, AD. 11 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:68)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1848 June 25- June 29, AD. 13 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:69)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1849 June 25- June 28, AD. 23 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:70)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1849 October 18, AD. 3 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:71)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1849 October 18, AD. 6 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:72)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1850 June 28- June 29, AD. 6 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:73)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1850 September 25, AD. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:74)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1851 June 26- June 30, AD. 11 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:75)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1853 June 25- June 30, AD. 26 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:76)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1853 September 1- September 2, AD. 9 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:77)
- Proceedings of the Visitors. 1854 June 26- June 29, AD. 24 pp. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:78)
- Memoranda of Joseph C. Cabell. [185-?]., ADs, 9 items. #2791-a. (Box-folder 2:79)
  Concerning passages of Jefferson correspondence omitted from Nathaniel Francis Cabell's Early history of the University of Virginia, as contained in the letters of Thomas Jefferson and Joseph C. Cabell, hitherto unpublished (Richmond, Va.: J. W. Randolph, 1856.)